（電気の音：ブーン…）
（同級生）ハア…
久しぶりじゃないか 乙骨(おっこつ)
Long time no see, Okkotsu.
Don't come near me.
（乙骨）こっちに来ないで…
Oh, come on, don't be so cold.
（同級生）おいおい
寂しいこと言うなよ
（乙骨の声）
I said don't.
Do you know how much
I've wanted to slug you?
俺がどれだけ オマエを
殴りたかったか
Just imagine how I've felt.
もっと俺の気持ちを
想像してくれ
（乙骨の声）
Right?
Stop it.
If you keep me on edge like this,
I might just kill you.
こんなに焦(じ)らされたら
うっかり殺しちゃうぞ？
Don't come near me!
（乙骨）来ちゃ駄目だ
里香(りか)ちゃん！
Rika-chan!
Huh? Rika?
あ？ リカ？
Record: November 2016, Tokyo Due to persistent bullying by classmates,
four male students, including the leader, suffered grave injuries.
（雷鳴）
（乙骨）ごめんなさい
I'm sorry.
ごめんなさい
ごめんなさい　ごめんなさい…
I'm sorry, I'm sorry...
ごめんなさい…
A complete cover-up and a secret execution?
（五条 悟(ごじょう さとる)）
完全秘匿(ひとく)での死刑執行
That's ridiculous.
あり得ないでしょ
The boy in question consented, though.
（総監部）
しかし本人が了承した
（五条）未成年…
16歳の子供ですよ
He's underage.
Just a 16-year-old child.
We also don't know how
many he'd curse to death.
逆に何人 呪い殺されるか
分かりません
He's already turned the tables
on three grade 2 sorcerers
現に二級術師が３人 一級術師が１人
返り討ちに遭ってるんです
and a grade 1 sorcerer.
だから僕にお鉢を回した
That's why you've turned to me.
Have you forgotten that?
それをお忘れですか？
（総監部）むう…
Then you're actually...
ではやはり…
Yes.
（五条）ええ　乙骨憂太(ゆうた)は
Okkotsu Yuta...
will be taken to Jujutsu High.
呪術高専で預かります
What is this,
これは何かな？
Okkotsu Yuta-kun?
乙骨憂太君
It used to be a knife.
（乙骨）ナイフ… だったものです
I tried to die,
死のうとしました
but Rika-chan interfered.
でも 里香ちゃんに
邪魔されました
That's dark.
暗いね
You're starting at a new school today.
今日から新しい学校だよ？
I'm not going.
行きません
ふーん…
I don't want to hurt anyone anymore,
（乙骨）もう誰も傷つけたくありません
so I'm not going outside anymore.
だからもう 外には出ません
But...
でも
living by yourself gets lonely.
1 人は寂しいよ？
The curse placed upon you
君にかかった呪いは—
is one that can save people, too,
depending on how it's used.
使い方次第で
人を助けることもできる
Tokyo Jujutsu High School
Learn how to use that power.
力の使い方を学びなさい
It's not like it'll be too late
全てを投げ出すのは
それからでも遅くはないだろう
to cast everything away after that.
JUJUTSU KAISEN
（鳥のさえずり）
Did you hear about the
transfer student coming today?
（パンダ）聞いたか？
今日来る転校生
They say he "stuffed” four of
his classmates into a locker.
クラスメイト 4人を
ロッカーに詰めたんだと
He killed them?
（真希(まき)）殺したの？
Tuna mayo?
（棘(とげ)）ツナマヨ？
No, but gravely injured, apparently.
いや 重傷らしい
Hmm... Well, if he's cocky, I'll wring him out.
ふーん
ま 生意気ならシメるまでよ
Bonito flakes.
おかか
I'll now... be introducing...
the transfer student!
転校生を
紹介
しやす！
Everyone, get excited!
テンション上げて　みんな！
Get excited.
上げてよ
I heard he's an awfully sour one.
随分 尖(とが)った奴らしいじゃん
I'm not going to create the mood
for someone like that.
そんな奴のために
空気作りなんてごめんだね
Salmon.
しゃけ
うーん…
フーッ
Oh, well.
まいっか
Come on in!
入っといでー！
I sense a really damp mood in there.
（乙骨の声）
ものすごく冷(さ)めた空気を感じる…
I ignore him.
（真希の声）シカトこいてやろ
Wha?!
あ゛？
乙骨憂太です…
I'm Okkotsu Yut--
（大刀が刺さる音）
Is this some kind of test?
（真希）これなんかの試験？
Hey.
おい
You're cursed.
オマエ 呪われてるぞ
This is a place to learn curses.
ここは呪いを学ぶ場だ
It's not a place for the cursed to be.
呪われてる奴が
来る所じゃねーよ
Huh?
？
The number of people that die
mysterious deaths or go missing
（五条）日本国内での
怪死者・行方不明者は
in Japan is over 10,000 a year on average.
年平均 1 万人を超える
Most of those are casualties of curses
そのほとんどが 人の肉体から
抜け出した負の感情—
born from the negative emotions of people.
“呪い”の被害だ
Among them are also malicious
cases caused by curse users.
中には呪詛師(じゅそし)による
悪質な事案(もの)もある
Only curses can affect other curses.
呪いに対抗できるのは
同じ呪いだけ
This is where we learn curses
to exorcise curses:
ここは呪いを祓(はら)うために
呪いを学ぶ—
Tokyo Jujutsu High School.
都立呪術高等専門学校だ
Tell me that ahead of time!
（乙骨の声）
事前に言ってよ…
（真希・パンダの声）え…
He just now told him that?!
今 教えたの？
Sorry.
（五条の声）メンゴ！
Oh, you all should hack away quickly.
あっ 早く離れたほうがいいよ
（真希・パンダ）え？
（パンダ・真希・棘)！
あ…
Do not...
（里香）ゆう゛だを゛ぉぉぉ
Wait! Rika-chan!
待って！ 里香ちゃん！
...bully Yuta!
（里香）虐(いじ)めるな
Special-Grade Cursed Human: Okkotsu Yuta
Special-Grade Cursed Apparition: Orimoto Rika
Record: Six Years Ago, Sendai City, Miyagi Prefecture
（子供たち）アハハハ…
ねぇ あっちあっち
Over there, over there!
What is it?
何 なに？
Happy birthday, Yuta.
（里香）憂太 誕生日おめでとう
ん？
ハハッ
Yay! Can I open it?
やったぁ！ 開けていい？
Go ahead.
（里香）いいよ
Huh? I can open it?!
（乙骨）え！ 開けていい!?
I said go ahead.
（里香）いいってば
（乙骨）アハハハ…
Wow!
Huh? A ring?
ん？ ゆびわ？
An engagement ring.
（里香）婚約指輪
Engagement?
（乙骨）こんにゃく？
It's a promise.
（里香）約束だよ
That when we both grow up,
we'll get married.
（祈本(おりもと)里香）里香と憂太は
大人になったら結婚するの
（急ブレーキの音）
（衝突音）
（通行人）キャー！
（通行人）マジか
Is this real?!
Hey!
Hey! Call an ambulance!
おい！ 救急車！
-Idiot! Look at her!
-Are they okay?
バカ　よく見ろ！
助かるわけねーだろ！
頭潰れてんだぞ！
-There's no saving her!
-What happened?
Her head's crushed in!
いや そう言ったって…
But still...
A child got run over by a car! Yes! Hurry!
子供が車に轢(ひ)かれて…
Help them!
そうです　早く！
I can't go near that!
Rika-chan?
…里香ちゃん？
Yuta...
（里香）ゆ゛ぅぅたぁ
（足を掴(つか)む音）
！
Yuta.
憂太
When we grow up,
大人にな゛ぁたぁら゛ぁ
we'll get married!
結婚する゛るるるるる゛ん゛…
It's a promise.
（里香の声）約束だよ
So as you can see,
（五条）ってな感じで
this is the boy cursed by Rika-chan,
who just loves him...
彼のことがだーい好きな
里香ちゃんに呪われてる—
Okkotsu Yuta-kun!
乙骨憂太君でーす
Be nice to him, everyone!
みんな よろしくー！
If you attack Yuta, Rika-chan's
curse will activate... or not.
憂太に攻撃すると
里香ちゃんの呪いが
発動したりしなかったり
Either way, be careful, everyone.
何にせよ みんな気をつけてねー
Say that sooner.
早く言えや
These guys are being all rebellious,
コイツら反抗期だから
僕がちゃちゃっと紹介するね
so I'll introduce them quick-like.
I have a feeling this teacher is the problem.
（乙骨の声）
この先生が悪い気がする…
This is the cursed tool user, Zen'in Maki.
（五条）呪具(じゅぐ)使い 禪院(ぜんいん)真希
She uses special tools to exorcise curses.
呪いを祓える特別な武具を扱うよ
This is the cursed
speech user, Inumaki Toge.
呪言師(じゅごんし) 狗巻(いぬまき)棘
He can only speak in rice ball ingredients,
so good luck conversing.
おにぎりの具しか語彙(ごい)がないから
会話 頑張って
Kelp.
こんぶ
This is Panda.
（五条）パンダ
I'm Panda. Nice to meet you.
パンダだ　よろしく頼む
Well, there you have it.
とまぁ こんな感じ
He didn't give me the
explanation I wanted most!
（乙骨の声）
一番欲しい説明がなかった…
Okay, now there are four first-years!
（五条）さぁ これで１年も
４人になったね
Three and one animal.
（乙骨の声）３人と１匹…
For your afternoon jujutsu practice,
午後の呪術実習は
２ー２のペアでやるよ
you'll be in pairs of two on two.
Toge, Panda, pair up.
棘・パンダペア
Let's do our best.
頑張ろう
Maki, Yuta, pair up.
真希・憂太ペア
Geh!
（真希）げっ
（乙骨）！
She just voiced disgust?!
（乙骨の声）
“げっ”って言った
U-Um, I-I hope we can work together.
（乙骨）あ… あの
よ… よろしくお願いします
You were bullied, weren't you?
オマエ イジメられてたろ？
！
Bull's-eye, huh?
（真希）図星か　分かるわぁ
私でもイジメる
I totally get it. Even I'd bully you.
（乙骨）…
Maybe it's because of your curse?
呪いのせいか？
It's written on your face that you're
branding yourself as a good person.
"善人です”ってセルフププロデュースが
顔に出てるぞ
It's sickening.
気持ち悪ィ
…
Why are you acting like the victim
when you're being protected?
（真希）なんで守られてるくせに
被害者ヅラしてんだよ
You've been passive your
whole life, haven't you?
ずっと受け身で生きてきたんだろ
Jujutsu High isn't so easy that
なんの目的もなくやってけるほど
you can get by without any goal.
呪術高専は甘くねぇぞ
真希！ それくらいにしろ！
Maki!
That's enough!
Bonito flakes.
おかか！
わーったよ　うるせぇな
Okay, fine. Get off my case.
Sorry about her.
すまんな
She has a habit of acting
like she understands others.
アイツは少々 他人を
理解した気になるところがある
No...
…いや…
She's right.
本当のことだから
ここは？
Where are we?
It's just an elementary school.
（五条）ただの小学校だよ
Huh?
（乙骨）え
Just an elementary school where
some children have gone missing.
ただの… 校内で
児童が失踪する小学校
"失踪"!?
Missing?!
It happens in places like this.
（五条）場所が場所だからね
It's probably the work of
a naturally-occurring curse.
恐らく自然発生した呪いに
よるものだろう
子供が呪いに
拐(さら)われたってことですか？
You're saying the kids
were kidnapped by a curse?
Yup.
そっ　今んとこ２人
Two so far.
Curses tend to settle in spots
大勢の思い出になる場所にはな
呪いが吹き溜まるんだよ
that many people have memories of.
Schools, hospitals...
学校　病院
Places often remembered with negative
emotions are a receptacle for them.
何度も思い出され
その度に負の感情の受け皿となる
As those emotions build up,
それが積み重なると
今回みたいに呪いが発生するんだ
they cause a curse to be born,
like it was here.
We're here to exorcise the curse
and save the children,
呪いを祓い 子供を救出
or if they're dead, retrieve them.
死んでたら回収だ
Huh? Dead?
え？ 死…？
Emerge from darkness, blacker than darkness.
"闇より出でて闇より黒く"
Purify that which is impure.
“その穢(けが)れを禊(みそ)ぎ祓え”
あ… 夜になってく
It's turning into night?
It's a veil.
“帳(とばり)”
It's a barrier that will smoke out the curse
君たちを外から見えなくし
呪いをあぶり出す結界だ
and keep you all from
being seen by those outside.
It's easy to undo from inside.
内側から簡単に解けるよ
Now, do be careful...
そんじゃ くれぐれも
死なないように
not to die.
D-Die? Sensei?!
死って…
（乙骨）先生！
（真希）転校生
Transfer student.
Don't get distracted.
余所見(よそみ)してんじゃねぇよ
Put... me... on?
（呪霊）は…
い…
る？
は… い…
Put me on?
る？
（乙骨）こ… こっちに来る！
I-It's coming this way!
Wh-Wh-What do we do?!
どどど… どうしよう！！
Don't scream.
（真希）わめくな
Remember this.
覚えとけ
The weaker curses are,
呪いってのはな
弱い奴ほどよく群れる
the more they group together.
Of course, the same could be said for humans.
まぁ そりゃ人間と同じか
Incredible...
（乙骨の声）すごい…
Just one blow...
一振りで
Come on, let's move it.
オラ　さっさと行くぞ
Huh? Where to?
（乙骨）えっ どこに？
Inside, obviously.
（真希）校内(なか)に決まってんだろ
うう… うう…
禪院さん　怖くないの？
Zen'in-san, aren't you scared?
Don't use my last name.
苗字(みょうじ)で呼ぶな
S-Sorry...
ごっ ごめん
But it really seems like
ghosts would be here.
でも… 滅茶苦茶出そうだよ
Though we've already seen some.
もう出てるけど
There aren't many curses here,
even though the veil's been drawn.
（真希の声）“帳”が下りているのに
呪いの数が少ない
No, they re here, just not attacking.
いや… いるのに襲ってこない
Is it because he's here?
まさか 乙骨(コイツ)がいるからか…？
Something just moved!
あ… 今 何か動いた
Hey!
（真希）おい
（乙骨）はい!?
Yes?!
What grade are you?
（真希）オマエ 何級だよ？
Huh? In English proficiency?
え？ 英検？
Jujutsu sorcerers are ranked
in grades from 4 to 1.
呪術師には四から一の
階級があんだよ
But I only just came to Jujutsu High.
（乙骨）でも僕 呪術高専
来たばっかだし
I don't think I have that.
そんなん ないんじゃ…
Ugh, forget it.
ああ… もういい
学生証見せろ
Show me your student ID.
You got one from that
dumb blindfolded guy, right?
バカ目隠しからもらったろ？
Dumb blindfolded guy?
バカ目隠し…
Yes, here you go.
はい　どうぞ
Well, if you joined with no prior history,
you're probably grade 4...
ま 前歴なしで入学なら
四級…
Tokyo Jujutsu High School Student ID — Special
Name: Okkotsu Yuta
DOB: 03/07/2001
This is proof that the individual listed above is a student.
Special-grade?!
（真希の声）特急!?
Special-grade is above
even grade 1, isn't it?
特急って…
一級のさらに上だろ
This sounds like it has to be a joke!
こんなん冗談でしか
聞かねーレベルだろ
Zenin-san'
This sounds like it has to be a joke!
（乙骨）…禪院さん
Zen'in-san! Zen'in-san!
禪院さん　禪院さん！
Behind you.
後ろ…
（窓が割れる音）
（呪霊）おおおおおおおお
チッ
Shit!
クソッ！
無駄にでけぇな！
You're way too damn big!
You bastard!
このぉー！
げ！
（ゴクン）
Thank, thank, thank you for the meal!
（呪霊）ごち… ごち…
ごちそぉさまぁあああん
Shit! Shit!
（真希）クソ！ クソ！
呪具 落とした！
I dropped my cursed tool!
Let us out, damn it!
出せ ゴラァ！
ここは？
Where are we?
We're in that curse's stomach!
あの呪いの腹の中だよ
こんくらいで気絶してんじゃねー
You shouldn't be passing out over this.
You mean it ate us?!
ってことは食べられたの!?
That's right!
そうだ　テメエ
呪いに守られてんじゃねーのかよ！
I thought you were being
protected by your curse?!
Even I don't know what
makes Rika-chan come out!
（乙骨）里香ちゃんがいつ出てくるか
僕もよく分からないんだ！
More importantly, what do we do now?!
それよりどうするの!?
After time passes and the veil
goes away, help will come for us.
（真希）時間がきて
“帳”が上がれば助けが来る
クッ…
This is embarrassing! Shit!
恥だ　クソ！
Help!
（子供）助けて
Huh?
あ？
（子供）お願い
こいつ 死にそうなんだ
Please! He's about to die!
You're saying the kids
were kidnapped by a curse?
子供が呪いに
拐われたってことですか？
Yup.
そっ　今んとこ２人
Two so far.
We're here to exorcise the curse
and save the children,
呪いを祓い 子供を救出
or if they're dead, retrieve them.
死んでたら回収だ
Thank goodness they're alive.
よかった　生きてた…
No, it's not good.
よくねぇよ
？
Look closer.
ちゃんと見ろ
The big one's obviously been
affected by the curse, too.
デカいほうも完全に呪いに
あてられてる
Both of them could die at any minute.
２人共
いつ死んでもおかしくねぇ
Oh, no...
そんな！ どうすれば…！
What do we do?!
There's nothing we can do!
どうにも！
助けを待つしかねぇよ！
We can only wait for help!
Not everyone has a resistance
to curses like you do!
誰もがオマエみてぇに
呪いに耐性があるわけじゃねーんだよ
？… 禪院さん？
Zen'in-san?
Zen'in-san?!
禪院さん!?
What's this wound?
なんだ この傷…
Are you cursed?
呪いがかかってるのか？
Is she going to die?
（子供）お姉ちゃん
死んじゃうの？
Please, save us, mister!
ねぇ？ 助けてよ お兄ちゃん！
ねぇ！
Please!
You keep asking, but I can't--
そんなこと言ったって…
無理だよ 僕…
Okkotsu!
（真希）乙骨
Seriously, why did you come
オマエ マジで何しに来たんだ
to Jujutsu High?!
呪術高専によ！
What do you want to do?!
何がしたい！
何が欲しい！ 何を叶えたい！
What do you want to have?!
What do you want to achieve?!
I... don't want anyone to get hurt anymore.
僕は…
もう誰も傷つけたくなくて
I tried to lock myself away and disappear.
閉じこもって消えようとしたんだ
But I was told it's
lonely being all by myself,
でも １人は寂しいって言われて
and I couldn't argue.
言い返せなかったんだ
I want to interact with someone!
誰かと関わりたい
I want to be needed by someone!
誰かに必要とされて
I want the confidence to
say it's okay that I'm alive!
生きてていいって
自信が欲しいんだ
Then exorcise them.
じゃあ 祓え
Exorcise curses, exorcise them,
exorcise them over and over!
呪いを祓って祓って
祓いまくれ！
Confidence and friends will
all come to you after that!
自信も他人も
その後からついてくんだよ！
That's the kind of place Jujutsu High is!
呪術高専は—
そういう場所だ！
Rika-chan.
里香ちゃん
What?
（里香）なぁに？
Lend me your strength.
（乙骨）力を貸して
イア゛ァア゛ア゛ア゛
あぉおぉ… だァれぇ？
Who are you?
Be quiet!
う゛う゛う゛う゛るさい
Now that's terrifying.
（五条）凄(すさ)まじいね
So this is the full picture of Orimoto Rika,
これが特級過呪怨霊
祈本里香の全容か
the special-grade cursed apparition?
ククク… 怖い怖い
So scary.
Wow!
わぁ きれぇ
So pretty!
I'm so pretty!
りか きれぇなの…
すきぃ！
I love it!
みんな…
Everyone...
もう少しだから
It's just a little further!
I need to get Sensei to check them all soon,
（乙骨の声）
早くみんなを先生に診せなきゃ
while Rika-chan's distracting the curses!
呪いが里香ちゃんの気を
引いてるうちに
つ！
I can't collapse yell
（乙骨の声）まだ 倒れるな…！
Not yet!
まだ！
I just decided I was going
to change, here and now!
ここで変わるって
決めたじゃないか！
You can do it,
（里香）頑張れ
Yuta.
憂太
うん
Yeah, I will!
頑張るよ！
Welcome back.
おかえり
You did well.
頑張ったね
They say both Maki and the kids will be fine.
（五条）問題ないってさ
真希も子供も
よかった
Thank goodness.
You don't look very satisfied.
何かスッキリしない顔だね
I managed to call Rika-chan
out myself for the first time.
初めて自分から
里香ちゃんを呼びました
Really? That's a step forward.
そっか　一歩前進だね
（乙骨の咳(せき)）
ゴホ… ゴホッ…
（乙骨）いっせーの！
One, two...
（里香の笑い声）
Stop, Yuta!
やめてよ　憂太
ハハハ… やめてって
I said stop!
Stop, Rika-chan!
（乙骨）やめてよ 里香ちゃん
There! Take that!
（里香）それっ 食らえ！
（２人の笑い声）
It's a promise.
（里香）約束だよ
When we both grow up, we'll get married.
大人になったら
里香と憂太は結婚するの
Sure!
（乙骨）いいよ
Then we'll be together forever and ever!
じゃあ ぼくらは
ずーっとずーっと
いっしょだね
What's wrong?
（五条）どうかした？
いえ…
Nothing...
Just remembering something.
少し思い出したんです
I don't think Rika-chan cursed me.
里香ちゃんが
僕に呪いをかけたんじゃなくて
I think I might have cursed Rika-chan.
僕が里香ちゃんに
呪いをかけたのかもしれません
This is my personal theory,
これは持論だけどね
but there's no curse more twisted than love.
愛ほど歪(ゆが)んだ呪いはないよ
Sensei.
（乙骨）先生 僕は呪術高専で—
While I'm at Jujutsu High,
I'll break Rika-chan's curse.
里香ちゃんの呪いを解きます
（ドアの開く音）
The special-grade cursed
apparition, Orimoto Rika,
（総監部）特級過呪怨霊 祈本里香
422秒の完全顕現
was fully manifested for 422 seconds.
We entrusted you with Okkotsu
precisely to prevent this sort of thing.
このような事態を防ぐために
乙骨を君に預けたのだ
There's no room for excuses,
申し開きの余地はないぞ
五条悟
Gojo Satoru.
Well, I never planned on making any excuses.
まあ 元々言い訳なんて
するつもりないですし
How can you joke about this?!
（総監部）何をふざけている！
If Orimoto Rika had remained out of control,
祈本里香が
あのまま暴走していれば
she could have wiped out an entire town!
町１つ消えていたかも
しれんのだぞ！
I would have risked my life to stop her.
そうなりゃ命懸けで止めましたよ
Listen, there's only one thing
we can say about that curse:
あのね 私らがあの呪いについて
言えることは１つだけ
"I don't understand.”
“出自不明(わからない)”
Why did a little girl who wasn't
from any line of jujutsu sorcerers
呪術師の家系でもない
女児の呪いが
become such an immense curse?
どうしてあそこまで
莫大なものになったのか
We can't control something
we don't understand.
理解できないモノを
支配(コントロール)することはできません
So it'll take trial and error.
ま トライ&エラーってね
しばらく放っておいて下さいよ
Just leave it alone for a while.
Do not forget that Okkotsu's
secret execution was only suspended.
（総監部）乙骨の秘匿死刑は
保留だということを忘れるな
And don't you forget
（五条）そうなれば
that if it comes to that,
I'll side with Okkotsu.
私が乙骨側に付くことも
忘れずに
Christ, damn rude geezers.
（五条）ったく
野暮な年寄りどもめ
I don't ever want to become like them.
ああはなりたくないね
I'll have to be careful.
僕も気をつけよっと
Besides,
大体さぁ 若人から
青春を取り上げるなんて
no one's allowed to take
youth away from young people.
許されていないんだよ
ハァハァハァ…
Maki, Toge, last lap.
真希と棘　ラスト１周！
No one is.
何人(なんぴと)たりともね
Well, go ahead.
ささ どうぞ
S-Sure...
あ… はい
はぁ…
It's nearly impossible to exorcise
a curse as big as Orimoto Rika.
（五条）祈本里香ほどの
大きな呪いを祓うのは ほぼ不可能
However, breaking it is a different story.
だが“解く"となれば話は別だ
You have to read the thousands, maybe
tens of thousands, of knots of cursed energy,
何千何万もの呪力の結び目を読み
and unravel them one by one.
1 つずつほどいていく
It's a method that can only be pursued
by you, the one she's cursed.
呪われている君本人にしか
できないやり方だ
What exactly do I do?
具体的にどうすれば…
Use this.
これを使うといい
うわっ
A katana?
刀…！
Curses are most stable when
they're possessing an object.
（五条）呪いは物に憑(つ)いてる時が
一番安定するからね
Back then, you used that ring
to connect to Orimoto Rika.
君はあの時 指輪を通して
祈本里香と繋がった
The pipeline's already there.
パイプはできてるんだ
So now you need to borrow part of Rika's curse,
里香の呪いをもらい受け
刀にこめて支配する
imbue it into the katana, and control it.
Increase the amount as you repeat it,
繰り返し量を増やし
いずれは全てを手中に納める
and eventually you'll have
all of it under your control.
Then you're free.
あとは晴れて自由の身さ
Both you and her.
君も彼女もね
Imbue the curse into the katana...
刀に呪いをこめる…
And at the same time...
と同時にぃ 刃物の扱いも
覚えなきゃだし
You need to learn how to wield a blade!
You're super weak, after all.
何より君
超貧弱だから
First, we'll have to train you thoroughly.
まずは徹底的にシゴきます
（セミの鳴き声）
！
お
Tuna.
ツナ
Hey, hey, everyone!
（五条）やぁやぁ みんな
調子はどうだい？
How's it going?
あっ えーと…
Oh, uh...
Don't get distracted.
余所見してんじゃねぇよ
はい
Right.
（真希）さっさと構えろ　ハゲ
Take your stance already, idiot!
She's ruthless!
（乙骨の声）きっつ！
はい…
Right!
You're going to land a
blow on me, aren't you?
私から一本取るんだろ？
はい！
Yes!
（乙骨の声）かわされた！
She dodged that?!
But she's off-balance!
けど崩した！
I get her on the landing!
着地で捉(とら)える！
嘘ぉ！
No way!
はい　死んだ
There, you're dead.
I win again.
また私の勝ちだな
Was that last part necessary?
最後の要りました？
Don't be soft.
甘えんな
You should always treat
it like it's a real battle.
常に実戦のつもりでやれ
罰(いたみ)があるのとないのとじゃ
成長速度がダンチなんだよ
Pain or the lack thereof makes a
huge difference in how fast you grow.
That's right. I'm...
（乙骨の声）そうだ　僕は…
One more, please!
（乙骨）もう一本
お願いします
I'm going to break Rika-chan's curse!
（乙骨の声）僕は里香ちゃんの
呪いを解くんだ！
It's been three months since
Yuta came to Jujutsu High.
（パンダ）憂太が高専にきて３か月か
His movements have gotten a lot better.
かなり動けるようになったな
Salmon.
しゃけ
His personality is more positive now, too.
性格も前向きになったよねぇ
すじこ
Salmon roe.
Maki looks like she's having fun, too.
確かに真希も楽しそうだ
Before now, she didn't get to spar
much with a fellow weapon--
今まで武具同士の立ち合いって
あんまなかっ…
Revelation!
（パンダの声）天啓(てんけい)
Yuta! Hey, come here!
憂太ァ！ ちょっと来い！
カマン！
Come on!
（乙骨）え？
Huh?
What's up, Panda-kun?
どうしたの パンダ君？
A super important discussion! Listen closely!
超大事な話だ！ 心して聞け！
Do you prefer big boobs or small boobs?
お前 巨乳派 微乳派？
Right now?!
（乙骨の声）今!?
I've never really given it much thought...
Sexy Talk
いや… あんまり気にしたこと
ないんだけど…
ふんふんふんふん
But I suppose I prefer them somewhat big?
人並みに大きいのは好きかと…
ほっほーう
Oh-ho?
Maki!
真希！
Huh?
あ？
You've got a chance!
脈ありデース
Chance! Chance! Chance!
What crazy ideas are you getting?
I'll kill you!
（真希）何 勘違いしてんだ
殺すぞ！
（パンダ）照れんなや
小学生か
Don't be so shy!
Are you an elementary schooler?
All right, I'll kill you!
（真希）おーし 殺す！
ワシントン条約とか関係ねぇかんな
I don't give a damn about CITES!
What's this about?
ハハ… 何の話かな
Kelp.
…こんぶ
（乙骨の声）狗巻君のことは
まだ よく分かんなくて
I still don't really understand Inumaki-kun,
so he's a little scary...
ちょっとだけ怖かったり…
（手を叩く音）
Okay, gather round!
はーい　集合
You two, continue your training.
そこの２人は
引き続き鍛錬してもらって
Toge, you've been requested.
棘 ご指名　君に適任の呪いだ
It's a curse you're perfect for.
Go exorcise it quickly.
ちゃちゃっと祓っておいで
Salmon.
しゃけ
Requested?
ご指名…
Toge's the only grade 2
sorcerer among us first-years.
棘は１年で唯一の二級術師
単独での活動も許されてんの
He's allowed to take missions on his own.
へぇ〜 すごいなぁ
Wow, that's impressive.
（真希の声）オマエ特急じゃん
You're a special-grade.
You go with him, Yuta.
憂太も一緒に行っといで
棘のサポートだ
You'll be Toge's support.
Huh? Support?
えっ サポート…
Well, more like an observer, really.
（五条）ってよりは見学だね
There's a wide variety of jujutsu,
呪術は多種多様
So you can assume there are as many ways
to exorcise a curse as there are sorcerers.
術師の数だけ祓い方があると
思ってくれていい
Toge's cursed speech is one good example.
棘の“呪言"はそのいい例だ
Make sure to learn from him.
しっかり勉強しておいで
Cursed speech?
“呪言”？
As the term suggests,
it's imbuing speech with curses.
（五条）文字どおり
言葉に呪いがこもるのさ
Well, it'll make sense once you see it.
ま 見たほうが早いよ
To break a curse,
you must first understand curses.
呪いを解くなら
まずは呪いを知らなきゃね
（乙骨の声）初めての実戦…
いや ２回目か
My first real mission...
No, my second.
I'm so nervous!
緊張するな…
しゃけ
Salmon.
Huh?!
ヒイッ
Oh, I-I'm sorry...
え… あっ ご… ごめんなさい…？
Yuta, one second.
憂太　ちょっと
あ はい
Yes?
悪いね　今回 引率できなくて
Sorry, I won't be able to
supervise this time.
でも まぁ
But the job is one Toge could
typically handle on his own,
本来 棘だけで足りる仕事だから
気楽にいきな
So you can take it easy.
君が気をつけるのはただ１つ
There's only one thing
you need to be careful of.
Don't let Rika out.
里香は出すな
There's no guarantee she'll go back
in like she luckily did last time.
前回みたいに
運よく引っ込んでくれるとは限らない
Only use what power of Rika's
that you can imbue in your sword.
里香の力は
刀に納まる範囲で使うこと
If you let her out fully again...
もしまた全部 出しちゃったら…
If I let her out?
出しちゃったら…？
You and I will both be killed!
僕と憂太 処分(ころ)されちゃうから！
Counting on you.
ヨロシクネ
Wha...
（乙骨の声）なっ…
Why does he have to rub salt
in that wound right now?!
なんでこの夕イミングで
追い打ちかけるの！
（カラスの鳴き声）
We've arrived.
（伊地知(いじち)）到着です
Every Tues/Fri get a 5x Point Bonus!
ハピナ商店街
Hapina Shopping District. Hapina Shopping District.
現在は ほぼシャッター街と
なってます
At this time, most of the
shutters here are closed.
Authorized Personnel Only No Trespassing
We're
closed.
"There's a project to demolish
the entire area and attract a shopping mall.”
ここら一帯を解体して
大型ショッピングモールを
誘致する計画がありまして
その視察中に
低級の呪いの群れを確認
"During an inspection of the area,
we confirmed a pack of low-level curses."
（伊地知潔高(きよたか)）狗巻二級術師には
その祓いをお願いします
"We'd like to request that the grade 2
sorcerer, Inumaki, exorcise them."
って アレ!?
狗巻術師!?
Huh? Wait, where's sorcerer Inumaki?
!? いない…
Not here?
Thank you.
（店員）ありあとやした〜
Oh, Ijichi-san, over there.
（乙骨）あっ 伊地知さん
あそこ
He was shopping?
（乙骨の声）買い物してる！
What did you buy?
何 買ったの？
!?
Throat Remedy
のど薬？
Throat medicine?
フゥ
In short, it would cause all
kinds of issues down the road
要は金をかけた建物に
日(いわ)くが付くと後々面倒なので
if the building they're spending so
much money on developed a bad history,
今のうちに祓ってくれとのことです
so they want us to exorcise it now.
Salmon.
しゃけ
Now, I'll draw the veil.
では “帳”を下ろします
Good luck.
ご武運を！
He said it was a pack of low-level curses.
呪い… 低級の群れって
言ってたよ
明太子
Pollack roe.
Hinoki Drug
Danger!
（ボコボコ）
That's not fair, Mama.
（呪霊たち）ずるいよ ママ
お兄ちゃんのほうが多いよ
Onii-chan got more.
So what? Let's trade doubles.
いいじゃん　ダブリは交換しよう
I smell olives.
（呪霊たちの声）
Reporting a lost child.
Cheap stuff! Cheap stuff!
It's not scary if you cross with everyone.
The weaker curses are,
the more they group together.
（真希）呪いは弱い奴ほど
よく群れる
Even so, there's just too many of them!
とは言っても
いくらなんでも多すぎじゃ
！
Inumaki-kun?!
…狗巻君!?
It's dangerous if you get that clo--
そんなに近づいたら危な…
「爆(は)ぜろ」
Explode.
This is cursed speech?
（乙骨の声）これが“呪言”…！
Huh? Oh... It's over already?
（乙骨）えっ あ そっか
えっ もう終わりか
Tuna mayo.
ヅナ゛マ゛ヨ゛
His voice is really worn out!
（乙骨の声）めっちゃ声 枯れてる！
Oh, that explains the throat medicine.
あ… だからのど薬
That's an incredible power,
すごい力だけど
それなりにリスクもあるんだな…
but it comes with a good deal of risk, foo.
（棘）おかか！
Bonito flakes...
What's wrong?
（乙骨）どうしたの？
あれ？ 本当だ　“帳”が上がらない
Huh? You're right.
The veil isn't lifting.
Huh?
あれ？
これじゃ出られないね
We won't be able to get out.
（２人）！…
What is this curse? Ifs presence is
nothing like the ones from before...
（乙骨の声）なんだ この呪い
今までのとは気配が…
（呪霊）ゾんば
Zomba.
（ドウン）
わっ 狗巻君！
Inumaki-kun!
Twist!
「捻(ねじ)れろ」
！
ゲホッ ゲホッ ゲホッ
What, what, what?! What is that?!
なになになに！ なに!? アレ!?
That curse...
（乙骨）呪いっ…
低級って言ってたのに！
He said they'd be low-level!
話が違くない!?
This isn't what we were told!
There's that thing's size, too.
あのサイズなのに
小学校のデカブツよりもずっと—
It's way scarier than the big guy
from the elementary school.
怖かった
That's right!
そうだ！ 狗巻君 ケガ…
指大丈夫!?
Inumaki-kun, you're hurt.
Is your finger all right?
Wow, that looks painful.
わ… 痛そう
Salmon.
しゃけ
ああ！ そんな
下手にイジんないほうが…
You shouldn't mess with it!
Sorry.
ごめん
It's my fault.
（乙骨の声）僕のせいだ
（乙骨の声）追ったり
こっちを探ってる様子はない
It doesn't seem to be pursuing
us or searching for us.
I'll contact Ijichi-san.
伊地知さんに連絡を
Enter Your Passcode
No Service
“圏外”…？
Out of service?
But why?
なんで？
お゛かが
Bonito flakes.
Huh?
え？
Because of the veil?
“帳”のせい…
“帳”が上がらない以上
祓うしかないん… だよね
If the veil won't lift,
then we have to exorcise it, right?
狗巻君
Inumaki-kun?
Should you be moving around already?
もう動いて大丈夫なの？
Kelp.
ごん゛ぶ　ゲホッ
え…
１人で行くってこと？
You're going to go alone?
（乙骨）ありがとう　狗巻君
Thank you, Inumaki-kun.
But I'm all right.
でも大丈夫だよ
Let's both do our best together!
２人で頑張ろう！ うん
（呪霊）オ゛？
Oh?
（里香）やっぢゃえ
ゆ゛う゛たぁあ
Get him, Yuta!
（呪霊）オ゛オ゛オ゛…！
（乙骨の声）お… 怒った！ なんで!?
ただでさえ おっかないのに！
It's mad?! Why?!
It was already scary enough!
フー フーッ
Don't take your eyes off him.
（乙骨の声）
目を離すな　足を止めるな
Don't stop moving.
Imbue the curse info the katana.
刀に呪いをこめる
Inumaki-kun is kind.
狗巻君は優しいんだ
He doesn't want to
accidentally curse others,
不用意に人を呪わないために
so he speaks in rice ball components--
words that cant carry curses.
呪いのこもらない
おにぎりの具で話してるんだよね？
Even today, he helped me out.
今日だって助けてくれた
危険から遠ざけようとしてくれた
He tried to keep me away from danger.
Even back then,
あの時も…
he was showing consideration
for my anxiety, wasn't he?
緊張してた僕に
気を遣ってくれてたんだよね？
Zora.
（呪霊）ゾゾ
ゾら
That was shallow!
（乙骨の声）浅い
ってゆーか硬い！
And he's tough!
I still can't compete with this curse, but ..
僕はまだこの呪いに適(かな)わない…
でも！
狗巻君！
Inumaki-kun!
I'll make sure to respond
to Inumaki-kun's kindness!
（乙骨の声）狗巻君の優しさには
絶対に
応える！
（ゴクッ ゴクッ）
Get crushed!
「潰れろ」！
Wow!
すご…
Mustard leaf!
（棘）高菜！
（乙骨）あっ 大丈夫大丈夫
カスっただけだから
Oh, I'm fine.
It's only a scratch.
Salmon.
しゃけ
Yeah, good work!
うん
お疲れ！
Once I break Rika-chan's curse,
（乙骨の声）
里香ちゃんの呪いを解いたら
I be a normal person.
僕はもう普通の人間
I won't be able to stay
at Jujutsu High anymore,
呪術高専には
いられなくなるけど
but until then,
それまでに少しでも
みんなの役に立ちたいな
I want to be useful to everyone.
Oh, what do we do about the veil?
（乙骨）あ “帳”どうしよう
（夏油(げとう)）残念
What a shame.
I came here to see this rumored Rika-chan.
噂の里香ちゃんを見に来たのに
As a fellow special-grade,
I was hoping to meet him soon.
同じ特級　早く挨拶したいなぁ
Tokyo Jujutsu High School Student ID — Special
Name: Okkotsu Yuta
DOB: 03/07/2001
This is proof that the individual listed above is a student.
I needed to deliver something he dropped, too.
落とし物も届けなきゃだし
（セミの鳴き声）
Toge's cursed speech
（パンダ）棘の“呪言”はなァ
is something he's been able
to use since he was born,
生まれた時から
使えちゃったから
so back in the day, he struggled quite a bit.
昔はそれなりに
苦労したみたいだ
Sometimes he cursed people
he never intended to curse.
呪うつもりのない相手を
呪っちゃったりな
His situation was rather similar to yours.
境遇としては憂太にかなり近い
That's why he's been worried about you
since the day you transferred in.
だから入学当初から
オマエを気にかけてたみたいでな
It's easy to misunderstand him,
誤解されやすいけど善(い)い奴なんだ
but he's a good guy.
I hope you'll be kind to him.
これからもよろしく頼む
Yeah, I'll--
うん　僕…
Come on, let's start morning training!
オラ 朝練 行くぞ！
（パンダ）フッフッフ
（乙骨）あ そっか
Oh, right.
Panda! What are you laughing about?!
パンダ 何笑ってんだ！
殺すぞ！
I'll kill you!
（パンダ）エー？ べっつにィ〜
Huh? It's nothing, though.
Maki-san, hey...
真希さん　ちょっと
あ？
I'd like to imbue my curse
刀に呪いをこめるの—
into my katana more smoothly.
Do you know any tricks?
もう少しスムーズに
やりたいんだけど 何かコツとか
知らねぇ
Nope.
Don't ask me about cursed energy.
呪力のことは私に聞くな
…？
…
I scoured every inch
of the shopping district,
（新田 明(にった あかり)）
商店街をくまなく捜索したところ
３種類の残穢(ざんえ)が
発見されましたっス！
and I found three different
types of residuals.
Even Ijichi-san said we weren't likely
to find any more than that.
これ以上は
もう何も見つからないだろうと
伊地知さんからっス！
Okay, got it. Thanks.
ん 分かった　ありがとう
You bet!
はいっス！
（フンフン）
Hinoki Drug
My apologies.
（伊地知）申し訳ございません
検証の結果 何者かが
私の“帳”の上から
Our inspection showed that someone
lowered a second veil on top of my own.
二重に“帳”を
下ろしていたことが判明しました
In addition,
加えて
a semi-first-grade curse made
an unexpected appearance.
予定にない準１級レベルの
呪いの発生
It's my fault for not being more thorough.
全ては私の不徳の致すところ
何なりと処分を
I'll accept any punishment.
いやいい　相手が悪すぎた
No, you're fine. You were just outclassed.
Meaning?
…と申しますと？
Do you have an idea who did it?
犯人に心当たりが？
Death to Fools Punishment
to the Weak Love to the Strong
（五条）夏油 傑(すぐる)
Geto Suguru.
4 人の特級術師が１人
One of the four special-grade jujutsu sorcerers,
who was banished from Jujutsu High
百を超える一般人を呪殺し
after cursing over a hundred
normal people to death.
呪術高専を追放された—
He's the worst curse user.
最悪の呪詛師だよ
Punishment to Death to Love to
（娘）ねぇ もういいって
帰ろうよ
Really, I'll be fine. Let's go home now.
It's all right. Just wait a little longer.
（母）大丈夫だから
もうちょっと待ってなさい
But...
でも…
So, you said your daughter
was being haunted by a ghost.
えーと お宅の娘さんが
霊に取り憑かれていると…
Isn't that right, Sato-san?
そういうわけだね　サトウさん
Ah, yes... um... it's Saito, though...
あ… はい　いや
私 斉藤です
No, you are Sato-san.
いや アナタはサトウさんです
That's what I've decided,
so Sato is better.
私がそう言ってるんだから
サトウのほうがいい
Uh-huh...
（母）はぁ…
お母さん　帰ろうよ
Mom, let's go home.
でも アンタ
最近まともに眠れてないでしょ
But you haven't been able
to sleep lately, right?
だからって
こんなうさんくさい…
This is so shady, though.
（夏油）刺すような視線を
常に感じている
You constantly feel
a piercing gaze upon you.
Sometimes your shoulders feel heavy,
and it gets hard to breathe, doesn't it?
肩が重く 息苦しくなる時が
ありますね？
Almost as if you've forgotten how to breathe.
呼吸の仕方を忘れたように…
And you often
そしてよく…
dream of being raped.
犯される夢を見る
なんでそのことを…
How did you know that?
Don't move.
動かないで
（娘）え…
Huh? No way... I feel much better!
えっ 嘘… すごい楽に
Honestly, I don't know how
we could ever repay you.
本当に何とお礼を
申し上げていいのやら
Oh, no, we should all help
each other in times of need.
いえいえ
困った時はお互い様です
Please rely on me anytime you need to.
またいつでも頼って下さい
オホホホ　ね 言ったでしょ
仏様のようなお人だった
See, I told you he was simply godly!
Yeah.
うん
Godly, huh?
（夏油）仏様ね…
よく分かってるじゃないか
You're a smart one, aren't you?
Filthy monkey who can't even use jujutsu.
呪術も扱えない猿共め
（菅田真奈美(すだまなみ)）
素が出てますよ　夏油様
Your true feelings are showing, Geto-sama.
The leaders have all gathered
in the meeting room.
幹部が揃いました
ミーティングルームへ
What are you doing?
…何をなさっているのですか？
It's disinfecting deodorant.
除菌消臭　みんなに
猿の臭(にお)いが移るといけない
I don't want everyone to
catch the monkey smell.
I'm so happy.
嬉しいなァ
How long has it been since we all gathered?
いつぶりかな　全員集合は
I know. Let's take a photo together
since we're all here.
そうだ　久しぶりに
みんなで写真を撮ろう
Where'd I put my single-lens?
（夏油）一眼どこだっけ？
（菅田）こちらに
Right here.
（シャッター音）
（金森(かねもり)）夏油！ 夏油を出せ！
Geto! Give me Geto!
Geto! Damn you!
夏油 貴様！
Well, if it isn't Kanemori-san.
これはこれは金森さん
そんなに慌ててどうされました？
What brings you here in such a panic?
とぼけるな！
早くわしの呪いを祓え！
Don't play dumb!
Hurry up and exorcise my curse!
Do you know how much I've paid you?!
オマエにいくら払ったと思ってる！
How much?
いくら？
Roughly one hundred and five million yen.
ざっつと 1 億とんで500万ですね
But there have been no donations
for the past six months.
しかし ここ半年間の寄付は
ありません
-Well--
-Ah... I guess that's it for you.
（夏油）あーあ もう限界かな
What are you sayi--
何を言って…
All monkeys have their own role.
猿にはね　それぞれ役割があります
There are money-collecting monkeys
金を集める猿と呪いを集める猿
and curse-collecting monkeys.
You're the former.
アナタは前者
If you're out of money,
I have no further use for you.
お人金がないなら用済みです
（ゴクン）
Screw you!
ふざけるな…
Suck, suck... Suck, suck...
（呪霊）ちゅうちゅうちゅう…
Suck, suck, suck, suck...
（ボジュ）
Disgusting.
穢らわしい
本当に同じ人間ですか？
Are they really the same species?
That's why I'm always saying
だから言っているだろう
非術師(かれら)は猿だ
they're monkeys.
The time is right, my family.
時が来たよ　家族たち
猿の時代に幕を下ろし
呪術師の楽園を築こう
Let's lower the curtain
on the age of monkeys
and build a paradise for jujutsu sorcerers.
First, we must fell the
cornerstone of the jujutsu world,
まずは手始めに—
呪術界の要 呪術高専を
Jujutsu High.
落とす
ん？
What's the matter, Yuta?
（パンダ）どーした 憂太？
Uh, well... I just had a bad premonition.
えーっと
なんかちょっと嫌な感じが…
You're imagining things.
気のせいだ
気のせいだな
Yep, imagining things.
Bonito flakes.
おかか
Huh?
ええ…
Guys, wait...
ちょっと みんなぁ
Well, your ability to sense
cursed energy sucks, you know.
（パンダ）だって憂太の呪力感知
超ザルじゃん
Figures it'd be dulled, with something
like Rika constantly with you.
（真希）まぁ 里香みたいなのが
常に横にいりゃ 鈍くもなるわな
Tuna.
（棘）ツナ
（夜蛾正道(やが まさみち)）
いまだ夏油の動向はつかめん
We still aren't picking up on
any actions from Geto.
Are you sure you're not worried over nothing?
やはり お前の杞憂(きゆう)じゃないのか？
Principal, I'm sad to say that's not possible.
学長　残念ながら
それはあり得ないです
I confirmed it myself on the scene.
直接 現場を確認しました
There's no way I would mistake
the residuals of Suguru's cursed energy.
僕が傑の呪力の残穢を
間違えるわけないでしょ
…傑…
Suguru...
ガッデム！ 噂をすればだ！
God damn it!
Speak of the devil!
Gather all sorcerers on campus, semi-first-grade
and above, in the circle out front!
校内の準一級以上の術師を
正面ロータリーに集めろ！
That's unusual.
珍しいな
Yuta's intuition was correct.
憂太の勘が当たった
しゃけ
Salmon.
？
You're... not staff.
関係者… じゃねぇよな
見ない呪いだしな
I haven't seen that curse before.
Salmon roe.
すじこ
Wow, big bird!
わー でっかい鳥
This place never changes.
変わらないね　呪術高専(ここ)は
Yuck! Geto-sama, is this really Tokyo?
（枷場菜々子(はさば ななこ)）うぇ〜 夏油様ァ
本当にココ東京ォ？
田舎くさァ
Feels like the sticks.
Nanako, that's rude.
（枷場美々子(みみこ)）菜々子… 失礼
What? But don't you think so, too, Mimiko?
えーっ 美々子だって
そう思うでしょ？
Come on! Get off already!
（ラルゥ）んもう！
さっさと降りなさい！
Aren't you cold?
（菜々子）アンタ 寒くないの？
（美々子）アイツら… 何…？
Who are they?
Whoa, it's a panda!
（菜々子）あー パンダだー！
かわいー！ 、
How cute!
And who are all of you?
オマエらこそ何者だ？
侵入者は許さんぞ
Intruders aren't allowed in, by Yuta-san here.
憂太さんが
Kelp!
こんぶ！
Huh?
え！
Go home before you get beaten!
殴られる前にさっさと帰んな！
By Yuta-san!
憂太さんに
Huh?!
ええ!?
Nice to meet you, Okkotsu-kun.
（夏油）はじめまして　乙骨君
私は夏油傑
I'm Geto Suguru.
（真希・パンダの声）速い！
He's fast!
Huh? Oh... Nice to meet you...
えっ あっ はじめまして
You possess a truly wonderful power, I see.
君はとても素晴らしい力を
持っているね
I believe that
私はね 大いなる力は—
great power ought to be used toward great ends.
大いなる目的のために
使うべきだと考える
Have you ever questioned
the current state of the world?
今の世界に疑問はないかい？
This world where jujutsu
sorcerers act in secret
一般社会の秩序を守るため
呪術師が暗躍する世界さ
in order to protect the order
of commonplace society.
つまりね
強者が弱者に適応する—
You see, there's this established paradox
saying the strong must accommodate the weak.
矛盾が成立して
しまっているんだ
It's so deplorable!
なんって嘆かわしい
はあ…
Uh-huh...
The apex of all creation has
halted its own path of evolution!
万物の霊長が
自ら進化の歩みを
止めてるわけさ
It's nonsense!
ナンセンス！
It's high time mankind reconsidered
its strategy for survival!
そろそろ人類も生存戦略を
見直すべきだよ
Which is why we'd like you to help us.
だからね
君にも手伝ってほしいわけ
Help with what?
何をですか？
We're going to kill all non-sorcerers
非術師を皆殺しにして
呪術師だけの世界を作るんだ
and create a world
with only jujutsu sorcerers.
What ..
（真希の声）何…
...Is he saying?
（パンダの声）言ってんだ？
Could you stop preaching your
crazy beliefs to my students?
（五条）僕の生徒に—
イカれた思想を
吹き込まないでもらおうか？
Satoru! Long time no see!
悟ー！ 久しいねー！
First of all, get away from those kids, Suguru.
まずその子たちから離れろ　傑
I had heard this year's first-years
were all outstanding students.
今年の１年は粒揃いと聞いたが
なるほど　君の受け持ちか
Now I understand.
It was all your doing.
A special-grade cursed human,
特級被呪者
a cursed corpse mutation,
突然変異呪骸(じゅがい)
the descendant of the cursed speech users,
呪言師の末裔(まつえい)
and...
そして
the Zen'in clan's failure.
禪院家の落ちこぼれ
テメエ
You piece of...
Watch what you say.
発言には気をつけろ
君のような猿は
私の世界には要らないんだから
Because I don't need any
monkeys like you in my world.
（乙骨）ごめんなさい
I'm sorry.
夏油さんが言ってることは
まだよく分かりません
I don't really understand
what you're talking about,
but...
…けど
友達を侮辱する人の
手伝いは
I can't help anyone who insults my friends!
僕にはできない！
My apologies. It wasn't
my intention to upset you.
…すまない
君を不快にさせるつもりはなかった
Then what exactly did you come for?
じゃあ一体
どういうつもりでここに来た
宣戦布告さ
To declare war.
Everyone gathered here,
お集まりの皆々様
open your ears and listen closely!
耳の穴かっぽじって
よーく聞いて頂こう
On the coming December 24th,
when the sun sets,
来たる12月24日
日没と同時に
我々は“百鬼夜行”を行う
we shall conduct the Night
Parade of a Hundred Demons.
！
場所は呪いの坩堝(るつぼ)—
It will take place in the crucible of curses,
Shinjuku, Tokyo...
東京 新宿
Kabuki Town, First Street
and the holy land of jujutsu,
呪術の聖地 京都
Kyoto.
We will unleash a thousand
curses upon each place.
各地に千の呪いを放つ
And of course, their command will be "massacre.”
下す命令はもちろん“鏖殺(おうさつ)”だ
If you wish to avoid a scene straight out of hell,
地獄絵図を描きたくなければ
死力を尽くして止めにこい
come and stop it with all your might.
Let us freely
思う存分
curse each other!
呪い合おうじゃないか
あー！ 夏油様
お店閉まっちゃう
Geto-sama!
The store's gonna close!
もうそんな時間か
It's already that late?
すまないね 悟
I'm sorry, Satoru.
彼女たちが竹下通りのクレープを
食べたいと きかなくてね
These girls just insist on getting
crépes from Takeshita Street.
早く！
Hurry!
お暇(いとま)させてもらうよ
So I'll be taking my leave.
いやはや
あんな猿の多い所の何が
Good grief. I don't see what's so good
about a place with so many monkeys.
このまま行かせるとでも？
Did you think we'd just let you leave?
You don't want to do that.
やめとけよ
（呪霊）おおお…
おおお…
Your precious students are within my range.
（夏油）かわいい生徒が
私の間合いだよ
Well, everyone, see you on the battlefield.
それでは皆さん　戦場で
Survival of the weakest.
（夏油）弱者生存
それがあるべき社会の姿さ
That's the proper form society should take.
弱きを助け 強きを挫(くじ)く
It should help the weak
and discourage the strong.
Listen, Satoru.
いいかい 悟
Sorcerers exist to protect non-sorcerers.
呪術は非術師を守るためにある
That's your argument?
（五条）それ 正論？
俺 正論嫌いなんだよね
I hate righteousness.
Are you the strongest
because you're Gojo Satoru?
（夏油）君は五条悟だから
最強なのか？
Or are you Gojo Satoru
because you're the strongest?
最強だから五条悟なのか？
（五条）何が言いてぇんだよ
What are you trying to say?
もし私が君になれるのなら
If I could become you,
このバカげた理想も
地に足が着くと思わないか？
then wouldn't my foolish ideals
become reasonable possibilities?
生き方は決めた
I've decided how to live my life.
All that's left is to do what I can
to the best of my ability.
あとは自分にできることを
精いっぱいやるさ
Geto Suguru.
（伊地知）夏油傑
呪霊操術を操る特級呪詛師
A special-grade curse user who
uses cursed spirit manipulation.
He's able to draw in and manipulate
naturally occurring, unbound curses.
主従制約のない
自然発生した呪いなどを取り込み
操ります
設立した宗教団体を呼び水に
It seems he's established a religious group
to collect curses from its followers.
信者から
呪いを集めていたようです
元々 所持していた呪いも
あるハズですし
He should still have the curses
he previously possessed,
ここ数年 呪いの報告数が
減少傾向にあったことも考慮すると
and considering the declining trend in the
number of curses reported in recent years...
His claim to possess
2,000 may not be a bluff.
数 2000というのも
ハッタリではないかもしれません
Even so, statistically, most of them
have to be weaklings at grade 2 or below.
だとしても 統計的には
そのほとんどが２級以下の雑魚
Even with a generous estimate,
there can't be much more than 50 curse users.
呪詛師だって
どんなに多く見積もっても
50そこらだろう
That's actually the scary part.
そこが逆に怖いところですね
I find it hard to believe he'd
start a war he couldn't win.
アイツが素直に
負け戦を仕掛けるとは思えない
ガッデム！
God damn!
Put out a call for aid to all alumni,
the three major clans, and even the Ainu Jujutsu Society.
OB OG それから御三家
アイヌの呪術連にも
協力を要請しろ
It's all-out war!
総力戦だ
This time, that curse, Geto, will be completely
今度こそ夏油という呪いを完全に
exorcised!
祓う！
That's what that muscle-brained principal
is probably spouting right now.
…とか息巻いてんだろうな
あの脳筋学長
December 24th, Day of the Night Parade of a Hundred Demons
（夏油）お互い
本気で殺(や)り合ったら
If we seriously tried to kill each other,
our chance of success would be about 30%.
こつちの勝率は
３割ってとこかな
（補助監督）ううっ
ああ… はっ は…
ああっ…
If the Jujutsu Society joins in as well,
呪術連まで出てきたら
２割にも満たないだろうね
we'll barely have a 20% chance.
However,
だが そのなけなしの勝率を
９割９分まで引き上げる手段が
there's just one move that makes
that slim chance of victory
jump straight to 99%.
１つだけあるんだよ
I kill Okkotsu Yuta and obtain the special-grade
cursed apparition, Orimoto Rika.
乙骨憂太を殺して
特級過呪怨霊—
祈本里香を手に入れる
学生時代の嘘(ブラフ)を
まだ信じているとは
They still naively believe
my bluff from my time in school.
めでたい連中だ
主従制約があろうとなかろうと
It doesn't matter if
the cursed spirit is bound.
首を私とすげ替えてしまえば
So long as I kill its master,
呪いなんていくらでも
取り込めるんだよ
I can absorb any curse I want.
With such high odds of victory,
勝率の高い戦で
高専が乙骨というカードを
切ることはない
the school won't use Okkotsu
as one of their cards.
After all, there's a chance he could
wipe out both enemies and allies.
下手を打てば
敵も味方も全滅だからね
The true purpose of the
Night Parade of a Hundred Demons
百鬼夜行の真の目的は
乙骨を孤立無援に追い込むこと
is to get Okkotsu isolated and unprotected.
Now, let's raise the curtain on a new age.
さぁ
新時代の幕開けだ
…なーんか
It sounds like...
とんでもないことに
なっちゃったなー
something crazy is going down.
あ… 真希さん
Maki-san!
What are you doing here?
何してんだ　今週は休講だろ
Classes are canceled for the week.
Well, I just felt kinda restless.
あ… いや
なんか落ち着かなくて
No one in the dorms is around, either.
寮の人たちも全然いないし
That's because the second-years
were dispatched to Kyoto earlier.
２年は前から
京都に遠征中だったからな
Toge and the third- and fourth-years
are in Shinjuku as backup.
棘は３、４年と
新宿でバックアップ
The principal really likes Panda, too,
パンダは学長のお気に入りだからな
多分 棘と一緒だろ
so he's probably with Toge.
I see.
（乙骨）そっか…
Ask.
（真希）聞けよ
（乙骨）えっ!?
Huh?
You've been curious, right?
気になってんだろ？
なんで私が落ちこぼれか
About why I'm a “failure".
あ… いや
Well, um... yes.
うん… はい…
ハァ…
My family, the Zen'in clan,
ウチ… 禪院家はな
御三家って呼ばれる
エリート呪術師の家系なんだよ
is one of the elite families of jujutsu
sorcerers known as the three major clans.
Do you know what the minimum requirement
to be a jujutsu sorcerer is?
オマエ 呪術師に必要な
最低限の素質って分かるか？
Huh? What is it?
えっ 何かなぁ？
う… うーん
（真希）呪いが“見える”ことだ
It's being able to see curses.
Oh, right.
あ そっか
一般人でも死に際とか
特殊な状況で見えることがあるけどな
Ordinary people can sometimes see them
in special circumstances, like at death's door,
but I can't see curses
without these lame glasses.
私はこのダセェ眼鏡がねぇと
呪いが見えねぇ
私の呪具は
初めから呪力がこもってるモンで
The cursed tools I use are already
imbued with cursed energy.
私がどうこうしてるわけじゃねぇ
It doesn't come from me.
…
Though, thanks to that,
I got out of that family.
おかげで家 出られたけどな
飯は不味(まじ)ぃし 部屋は狭ぇし
The food was awful, the rooms were small,
知らねぇオッサンが
うろついてっし
and it was crawling with old men I didn't know.
本っ当 最悪だったわ！
It seriously sucked!
Don't use my last name.
苗字で呼ぶな
誰もがオマエみてぇに
呪いに耐性があるわけじゃねーんだよ
Not everyone has a resistance
to curses like you do!
呪力のことは私に聞くな
Don't ask me about cursed energy.
Why are you still a jujutsu sorcerer, then?
（乙骨）真希さんは
どうして呪術師を続けるの？
Because I'm spiteful.
私は性格悪ぃかんな
呪いも見えねぇ奴が
一級術師として出戻って
I'm going to make that family cry
when I return to them
家の連中に
咲え面かかせてやるんだ
as a grade 1 sorcerer who can't see curses!
そんで 内から禪院家
ブッ潰してやる
Then I'll crush the Zen'in clan from within!
…んだよ
What?
（乙骨）いや
真希さんらしいと思って
Oh, I was just thinking that's so like you.
僕は…
I wish...
真希さんみたいになりたい
I could be like you.
強く真っすぐ生きたいんだ
I wish I could be so strong and unyielding.
I wish I had never given birth to you.
（真希の母）あんたなんか
生まなきゃよかった
You're the shame of the Zen'in clan!
禪院家の恥め！
Everyone,
みんな…
真希みたいになっちゃ駄目よ
you don't want to turn out like Maki.
If there's ever anything
I can help with, just ask.
僕に手伝えることがあったら
何でも言ってよ
Let's crush the Zen'in clan! Or something.
禪院家 ぶっ壊そー
なんて　ハハハ…
バーカ　１人でやるから
意味があんだよ
Moron. There's no point
if I don't do it by myself.
（乙骨）あ
（真希）部屋 戻るわ
I'm going back to my room.
（乙骨）うん　またね
Okay. Later.
…馬鹿か 私は
Am I an idiot?
認められた気に
なってんじゃねーよ
Don't start thinking this
means you've been accepted!
（夏油）“闇より出でて闇より黒く”
Emerge from darkness, blacker than darkness.
“その穢れを禊ぎ祓え”
Purify that which is impure.
！
A veil was drawn over the school?
（乙骨）高専(がっこう)に“帳”が下りてる
But who... and why?
誰が… どうして
（呪霊）おおお…
Keep the destruction of buildings
and infrastructure to a minimum.
建物・インフラの破壊は
可能な限り避けろ
逃げ遅れた
一般人がいる可能性もある
There's a chance some civilians
still haven't evacuated.
見つけ次第 避難させろ
If you find any, evacuate them.
聞いてるのか 悟？
Are you listening, Satoru?
There's one guy who looks like trouble.
１人 面倒くさそうな奴がいるな
（ミゲル）成程 アノ包帯カ
I see. That bandaged guy.
Yes. We'll take on the rest.
えぇ 他は私たちで
引き受けます
何度も言いますが…
I've said this many times, but...
I know.
分カッテル
俺ラハ足止メデショ
We're only stalling them, right?
ノラリクラリ
Let's just take it easy and have
some fun until Geto finishes his job.
夏油ノ仕事ガ終ワルマデ
遊ビマショ
You're here?
君がいたか
Is it a problem if I am?
いちゃ悪ぃかよ
てめぇこそ
なんでここにいる？
What the hell are you doing here?
Sorry, but I don't have time
to chat with monkeys.
悪いが 猿と話す時間はない
Gojo-san!
（伊地知）五条さん！
I have a report!
報告が…
どうかされました？
What's the matter?
いや…
Well...
That guy loves to show off,
and he's not on the front lines?
（五条の声）あの目立ちたがりが
前線に出てこない？
Is he in Kyoto?
京都のほうか？
なら何かしら連絡があるだろ
We should have received
some kind of word if he was.
何でもない　どうした？
It's nothing. What's up?
こんな時にとは思いますが
早いほうがいいかと
I know this isn't the best time,
but I thought it wise to speak up sooner.
It's about the investigation into Okkotsu-kun
that you previously requested.
以前 調査を依頼された
乙骨君の件です
（五条）！
Panda! Toge!
パンダ！　棘！
What is--
どうした… ああ〜
No questions!
（五条）質問禁止！
I'm sending you two to
Jujutsu High right now!
今から２人を呪術高専に送る
Huh?!
はぁ!?
夏油は今 高専にいる
Geto is there now.
I'm absolutely, probably, certain!
絶対 多分 問違いない！
どっちだよ！
Which is it?!
If my intuition is right,
（五条）勘が当たれば
最悪 憂太と真希 ２人死ぬ
in the worst case,
Yuta and Maki could both die!
（棘・パンダ）！
I'll head there right after
I take care of that foreigner.
僕もあの異人を片付けたらすぐ行く
２人を守れ
Protect those two.
Sorry, but defend them with your lives!
悪いが死守だ！
-Salmon!
-Right!
（パンダ）応(おう)！
（棘）しゃけ！
！
（菅田）まさか… 気づかれた!?
No way... They figured it out?
This is why I said you should
at least prepare a stand-in.
（ミゲル）ダカラ影武者ノ１人デモ
用意シテオケバト
A bad dummy would only make things worse.
下手なダミーは逆効果
夏油様がおっしゃてたでしょ
That's what Geto-sama said.
Mimiko, Nanako!
美々子！ 菜々子！
What?
なーにー？
We're stepping up the plan. Engage.
（菅田）予定を繰り上げます
開戦よ
（美々子・菜々子）ふふ…
I've been waiting for this!
待ってましたぁ！
I'm your opponent,
アンタノ相手ハ
俺ダヨ
special-grade.
特級
Sorry,
（五条）悪いけど
but I'm in a hurry right now.
今 忙しいんだ
A veil's been drawn!
（パンダ）“帳”が下りてる！
悟の勘が当たったのか…
Does that mean Satoru's intuition was right?
I'll break the veil!
俺が“帳”を破る！ あとは最短で…
Then we'll take the shortest route!
いくぞ！
明太子！
Pollack roe!
Oh?
（夏油）おっと
誰かが“帳”に穴を開けたな
Someone made a hole in the veil.
何事もそう思い通りには
いかないもんだね
Nothing ever goes quite as planned.
Should take them five minutes
from the point of entry to here.
侵入地点からここまで
５分ってとこか
Should I ignore them,
or should I take care of them?
無視するべきか
片付けておくべきか
It's so hard to decide.
迷うね
（破壊音）
They broke through all the walls
to take the shortest route?
（夏油の声）全ての壁を
ブチ破って最短できたか！
Not bad.
やるね
オラオラオラ！
！
Maki!
（パンダの声）真希！
よそ見
Focus.
This guy can handle close combat, foo?
（パンダの声）
こいつ 体術もいけるクチか
（ゴリラモード）ウォー
ほう
Oh?
Predictable.
ワンパターンだよ
フェイントだからな
Because it was a feint.
Drumming Beat!
激震掌(ドラミングビート)！
That was close.
惜しかったね
…お前もな…
Same to you.
Plummet!
「堕(お)ちろ」！
Toge! You okay?
棘！ 大丈夫か!?
Caviar.
い… ぐら
Yeah, Maki comes first.
ああ… まずは真希
Maki, are you okay?
真希… 大丈夫か？
Maki?
…真希！
Mustard leaf.
高菜…
N-Not yet...
ま… まだ… だ…
Huh?
（パンダ・棘）？
（地響き）
（乙骨）わっ…
Another quake?
また地震？
何が起きてるんだろ
I wonder what's going on.
（夏油）素晴らしい
素晴らしいよ
Wonderful.
Wonderful!
私は今！ 猛烈に感動している！
I am incredibly touched right now!
乙骨を助けに
馳(は)せ参じたのだろう!?
You all raced here to save Okkotsu, right?
Jujutsu sorcerers are sacrificing
themselves for a fellow sorcerer!
呪術師が呪術師を
自己を犠牲にしてまで
慈しみ！ 敬う！
Affection! Admiration!
The world I long for
私の望む世界が…
今 目の前にある！
is here before my eyes!
Maki-san?
真希さん？
To be honest,
本当はね
I wanted you to live, too, Okkotsu.
君にも生きていてほしいんだ
乙骨
But this is all for the
future of the jujutsu world.
でも全ては呪術界の
未来のためだ
Panda-kun...
（乙骨）パンダ君…
Yuta...
（棘）ゆ゛う゛だ…
（乙骨）狗巻君
Inumaki-kun...
逃… げ ろ…
Run... away...
Record: December 24th, 2017
Come out, Rika!
来い！ 里香！
Special-Grade Cursed Apparition, Orimoto Rika
Fully Manifested a Second Time
君を殺す
I will kill you.
I'll murder you!
ブッ殺してやる
（ドン！）
（ドン！ ドン！）
（破壊音）
Quantity before quality.
（夏油）まずは質より量
What's your move, Queen of Curses?
どう出る？ 呪いの女王
（呪霊）おおお…
（爆発音）
Rika.
（乙骨）里香
These three are horribly wounded,
especially Maki-san.
（乙骨の声）３人共 ひどい怪我(けが)だ
特に真希さん
ハッ… ハッ…
I won't let you die!
死なせない
ハッ… ハ… ハァ…
Not fair, not fair!
（里香）ずるい ずる゛い゛
お゛前ばっかり！
オ゛前ばっかり！
It's always you, always you!
（乙骨）何をしている 里香
What are you doing, Rika?
Huh?
あ゛っ
（乙骨）その人は僕の恩人だ
That woman saved me.
蝶よりも花よりも
丁重に扱え…！
Handle her with more care
than a butterfly or a flower!
あ゛…
I'm sorry, I'm sorry!
ごめんなさい　ごめんなさい！
怒らないで
Don't be mad.
怒ってないよ
I'm not mad.
嫌いにならないでぇ
Don't hate me.
I don't hate you.
（乙骨）嫌いになんてならないよ
Our enemy is that man there.
僕らの敵はアイツだよ
（里香）…憂太 アイツ嫌い？
Yuta, do you hate him?
Yeah, I loathe him.
（乙骨）あぁ　大嫌いだ
Then I hate him, too!
じゃあ 里香も嫌いぃいい゛
おかえり
Welcome back.
Why did you stop attacking?
（乙骨）なんで攻撃をやめた？
Healing with cursed energy requires
an advanced reverse cursed technique.
（夏油）呪力による治癒には
高度な反転術式を要する
君の意識を少しでも
そちらに割かせたほうが
It was more advantageous to let you
divide your attention over there.
得策だろう
Now, shall we start where we left off?
続きを始めようか
Rika, we're doing that.
里香　アレをやる
（夏油の声）“蛇の目”と“牙”
Snake Eyes and Fangs?
Those are...
あれは…
The cursed seals of the Inumaki clan!
狗巻家の呪印
（呪霊）あああああああ
Die.
「死ね」
（爆発音）
Wonderful!
素晴らしい
Cursed speech is a powerful technique
passed down in the Inumaki clan,
（夏油の声）“呪言”は
狗巻家相伝の高等術式
これを呪術を学んで
１年未満の少年がやってのけた
yet this young man pulled it off with
less than a year of studying jujutsu!
That really is hard to use.
やっぱり難しいや
呪力が拡散して
狙いが定まらない
The cursed energy scatters,
and it's hard to aim.
Inumaki-kun is incredible.
狗巻君はすごいなぁ…
So Orimoto Rika's true form
is ever-changing.
やはり祈本里香の正体は変幻自在
底なしの呪力の塊
She's an endless bundle of cursed energy.
Yes.
（乙骨）そう
My friends are amazing.
僕の友達はすごいんだ
それをオマエは…
And you! You!
オマエは…
ますます欲しいね
I want her even more.
I'll beat you to a pulp!
（乙骨）ぐちゃぐちゃにしてやる
でぇいっ
（猪野琢真(いの たくま)）フゥ…
Why is Nanami-san in Kyoto?
七海(ななみ)さーん なんで京都なんすか
俺の活躍 見てほしかったのに
I wanted him to see me shine!
（日下部(くさかべ)）うるせえ
（猪野）ん？
Shut up!
Quit griping and fight!
ブツクサ言ってねぇで 戦え
There are still more coming!
（日下部篤也(あつや)）まだまだ来るぞ
Man, what a pain.
ああ… メンドくせー
（冥冥(めいめい)）ふふ…
ふふふ…
フゥー これで50体
That makes fifty.
I've cleared the numbers
required for the incentive,
撃破数のインセンティブはクリア
満額ボーナス目指して
so now to work a little bit more
and aim for that full bonus.
もう少し働こうかな…
How old are you two?
君たち 歳は？
（菜々子）15ぉ〜
Fifteen.
You're still just children.
（伊地知）
まだ子供じゃないですか
今ならまだ引き返せます
It's not too late for you to turn back.
You don't know right from wrong, do you?
善悪の区別も
ついていないでしょう
カッチ〜ン
美々子ぉ アイツ ゲロムカつかねェ？
Annoying!
Mimiko, doesn't he totally piss you off?
Shall we hang him, Nanako?
吊るす？ 菜々子
アンタらは知らねぇだろ
None of you know, do you?
地図にも載ってねーような
クソ田舎で
Just how jujutsu sorcerers are treated out
in the damn sticks that aren't even on maps.
呪術師がどういう扱い受けてるか
Right or wrong?
善悪？ そんなんアンタらで
勝手にやってろし
You all can enjoy that by yourselves.
The way Geto-sama puts it,
夏油様が言えば
black is white, and white is black, too.
黒も白だし 白も黒なんだよ
We both believe in the world he's envisioned.
私たちはあの人が見据える
世界を信じてる
Anyone who gets in his way...
邪魔する奴は
...we'll hang!
吊るしてや…
（衝突音）
はぁ？
Huh?!
Miguel?
ミゲル？ アンタ何してんの
What are you doing?!
見テ分カレ！
Look, and figure it out!
You're tenacious.
（五条）しぶがといな
That rope...
（五条の声）あの縄 珍しい呪いが
編み込まれているな…
It has an unusual curse woven info it
It's disrupting my techniques.
こっちの術式が乱される
（ミゲルの声）
モウ半分モ残ッテナイ
I barely have half left.
How many decades do you think it took
コレ１本編ムノニ
俺ノ国ノ術師ガ
the sorcerers in my country
to weave this one rope?!
何十年カケルト思ツッテル！
Like I care.
（五条）知るか
僕の１秒のほうが勝ってる
One second of my time will outmatch it.
-Dummy!
-That's all there is to it.
それだけだろ
You're in my way.
邪魔だ
（爆発音）
Not good! Gajo-san's snapped!
（伊地知の声）
やばい　五条さん キレてる
So this is the Limitless
technique Geto mentioned.
（ミゲルの声）コレガ夏油ノ言ッテイタ
“無下限呪術”
It interferes on the atomic level,
原子レベルニ干渉スル
緻密ナ呪力操作デ
controlling space-time with precise
manipulation of cursed energy.
時空間ヲ支配スル
And what makes that all possible
ls the power of those eyes.
ソレヲ可能ニシテイルノガ
アノ目カ
ノルママデ アト12分強
Just over twelve more
minutes until my quota.
死ヌ気デ 逃ゲ切ル
I keep running for my life!
ウオッ
チッ
ウワォッ
Wow!
Ouch!
That last round was dangerous.
（ミゲルの声）
サッキノハヤバカッタ…
ヒットアンドアウェイニ徹シテ
アト10分弱ヲ全力デ耐エル
I focus on hit-and-run.
I'll give everything I've got
to endure these last ten minutes.
If I die, I'm cursing you, Geto!
死ンダラ崇(たた)ルゾ！ 夏油！
あ 家入(いえいり)さん
この子もお願いします
Ieiri-san, please look at this one, too.
I will. Set him down over there.
（家入硝子(しょうこ)）
ん そこ寝かせといて
Right!
（新田）はいっス
What were you all doing?
あなたたち 何をしてるの！
It's all right.
大丈夫っス
家入さんが治してくれるっスから
Ieiri-san will fix you up.
よろしくお願いします
We're counting on you!
Sheesh.
…ったく
You really forced a heap
of trouble on us, Gelo.
ホント面倒なこと
かましてくれたね 夏油
It's your first time experiencing
such violent emotion,
（夏油）生まれて初めての激情
呪力が体に満ち満ちているね
and cursed energy is
filling your body, isn't it?
身体能力の向上 万能感
五感が研ぎ澄まされているだろ
That heightening of physical prowess,
that sense of omnipotence...
Your senses must be sharpened, too.
The riff-raff are no match for you now.
鳥合(うごう)どもでは相手にならないね
直に叩くとしようか
I'll have to crush you myself.
Follow my lead, Rika.
あわせろ　里香
Mankind stands at the top of the food chain,
（夏油）
人は食物連鎖の頂点に立ち
yet they imagined the existence
of higher beings and called them gods.
さらに高位の存在を夢想し
“神”と呼んだ
おかしいと思わないか？
Don't you find that strange?
Especially when we jujutsu
sorcerers exist without belief.
夢想せずとも
我々 呪術師がいるというのに
（乙骨・里香）はぁ〜
（夏油の笑い声）
結局 非術師(さるども)は
In the end, those monkeys
just want to avert their eyes from the
existence of those better than them.
自分より秀でた存在から
目を背けたいだけなのさ
神になりたいなんて
子供じみたことを言うなよ！
Don't go saying childish crap
like you want to be a god!
You're missing the point,
（夏油）論点がズレてるよ
乙骨
Okkotsu.
（破壊音）
私が望むのは“啓蒙(けいもう)”ではない
“選民”だよ
What I long for isn't enlightenment.
It's a chosen people.
数が多いというだけで
There are times when the strong are buried and
oppressed by the weak due to sheer numbers.
強者が弱者に埋もれ
虐げられることもある
そういう猿どもの厚顔ぶりが
And I'm telling you that the audacity
of the monkeys who do that
吐き気を催すほど不快だと
私は言っているんだ
makes me so sick I could vomit.
憂太 憂太あ゛
Yuta, Yuta...
It's all right. I'm used to it now.
大丈夫　慣れてきた
Are we done debating?
問答は終わりかい？
He's even faster!
（夏油の声）さらに速い
（夏油）駄目じゃないか
You shouldn't have done that.
急にそんな呪いをこめちゃ
器がもたない
When you imbue a curse like that
too abruptly, the vessel won't last.
悟に教わらなかったかい？
呪いは少しず…
Didn't Satoru teach you that?
You imbue curses hit by--
You're not bad.
やるじゃないか
I don't understand!
（乙骨）分かんないよ！
I don't know about any
sorcerers outside of this school,
高専以外の呪術師のことなんか
知らないし！
so I don't know
お前が正しいかどうかなんて
if you're right or not!
僕には分かんない！
But in order to remain with all my friends...
でも僕が
みんなの友達でいるために
In order for me to believe
it's okay that I'm alive...
僕が！ 僕を！ 生きてていいって
思えるように！
オマエは
I have to kill you!
殺さなきゃいけないんだ
You're egotistical.
自己中心的だね
だが自己肯定か
Still, self-affirmation, huh?
生きていく上で
これ以上に大事なこともないだろう
There's probably nothing more
important than that in life.
In which case, I'll also use
my full force to kill you.
ならばこちらも
全霊をもって君を殺す
もう質も量も妥協しない
I won't compromise on quality
or quantity anymore.
知っているかい？
特級を冠する人間は４人
Did you know
there are only four people
crowned special-grade?
Among curses, there are sixteen.
呪いだと16体 存在する
This is one of them.
これはそのうちの１体
Special-grade potential apparition,
特級仮想怨霊
Tamamo-no-mae incarnate!
“化身玉藻前(けしんたまものまえ)”
On top of that,
さらに私が今 所持している
4461体の呪いを１つにして
I'll combine the 4,461
curses I possess into one,
and strike you with it.
君にぶつける
Cursed Spirit Manipulation, Supreme Art:
呪霊操術 極ノ番
Maelstrom.
“うずまき”
（呪術師）うぉー！
（ブシュッ）
（呪術師）うっ…
（ブシュ）
（呪術師）あ…
（呪術師）七海さん
Nanami-san.
I'll take care of it.
（七海建人(けんと)）ここは私が
（加茂憲紀(かも のりとし)）ふん！
New Shadow Style, Simple Domain!
（三輪 霞(みわ かすみ)）シン・陰流 簡易領域
Quick Draw!
“抜刀”
フゥ…
！
Don't let your guard down, Miwa!
（究極(アルティメット)メカ丸(まる)）
油断するな三輪！
Mechamaru, above!
メカ丸！ 上！
（銃声）
You, too.
（禪院真依(まい)）アンタもね
（加茂）みんな 警戒を緩めるな
Everyone, stay alert.
（西宮 桃(にしみや もも)）加茂君
２時の方向から呪霊７体
Kamo-kun.
Seven cursed spirits at two o'clock.
Roger that. Where did Todo go?
（加茂）了解
東堂(とうどう)はどこに行った？
（破壊音）
Oh, I think you'll see him soon.
（西宮）あー すぐ会えると思う
（連続した破壊音）
（東堂 葵(あおい)）フッ
Where have you been all this time, Todo--
（加茂）
今までどこに行ってたんだ　東堂
Wh-What is that cursed energy?
な… 何だあの呪力は…
That one's dangerous, Todo!
そいつは危険だ 東堂！
１人で突っ込むな
Don't rush in on your own!
Wait for back--
Starting at eight, the talk show's
（加茂）応援を…
（東堂）８時からのトーク番組
Christmas live special will be
（東堂）クリスマス特別
生スペシャルに
hosting Takada-chan!
高田(たかだ)ちゃんが… 出る！
I can't keep wasting any time here!
こんな所で
モタついてられるか！
Todo!
東堂！
Kamo-kun.
（西宮）加茂君
Another ten or more cursed spirits
are approaching from six o'clock.
６時の方向から
さらに10体以上の呪霊が接近！
ぐっ… 全員迎撃態勢を敷け！
Everyone, prepare to intercept them!
Jeez, there's no end to them.
…ったく　キリがないわね
いつんなったら終わんのよ
When is this going to be over?
Okkotsu.
（夏油）…乙骨
I'm truly glad I came to kill you
before you could fully wield Orimoto Rika.
君が祈本里香を
使いこなす前に殺しに来て
本当によかった
It's a promise.
（里香）約束だよ
When we both grow up, we'll get married.
大人になったら
里香と憂太は結婚するの
Sure.
（憂太）いいよ
Then we'll be together forever and ever!
じゃあ ぼくらは
ずーっとずーっと
いっしょだね
Rika.
（乙骨）里香
（里香）なぁ に
Yes?
Thank you for always protecting me.
（乙骨）いつも守ってくれて
ありがとう
Thank you for falling in love with me.
僕を好きになってくれて
ありがとう
Could you lend me your power one last time?
最期にもう一度 力を貸して
I want to stop him.
アイツを止めたいんだ
I don't need anything else after that.
その後は
もう何もいらないから
僕の未来も 心も体も
I'll give you my future,
my heart, my body, everything.
全部 里香にあげる
From now on, we'll truly be together forever.
これからは
本当にずっと一緒だよ
I love you, Rika.
愛してるよ　里香
Shall we die together?
一緒に逝こう？
（里香）あ゛っ あ゛あ゛あ゛あ゛
Yuta! Yuta!
憂太！ 憂太っあ゛！
I love, love, love you!
大大大大 大好きだよぉ
He's offering himself as a sacrifice to
release the limit on her cursed energy?!
（夏油の声）自らを生贄(いけにえ)とした
呪力の制限解除
クッ… そうくるか！
So that's how you want it, womanizer?!
女誑(たら)しめ！
That's rude.
（乙骨）失礼だな
It's pure love.
純愛だよ
Then I fight for justice!
ならばこちらは大義だ
（夏油）… 素晴らしい
Wonderful!
Absolutely wonderful!
本当に素晴らしいよ
Truly the power to change the world!
まさに世界を変える力だ
If I had Rika, there would be no need
to sneak around gathering curses.
里香さえあれば
せこせこ呪いを集める必要もない
Next time.
次だ　次こそ手に入れる！
Next time, I'll obtain her!
フッ…
You're late,
遅かったじゃないか
Satoru.
悟
To think you'd be the one here at my end.
君で詰むとはな
Is my family safe?
私の家族たちは無事かい？
Every last one of them managed to escape.
揃いも揃って逃げ果(おお)せたよ
京都のほうも オマエの指示だろ？
The ones in Kyoto were
under your orders, too, right?
Yeah.
まぁね　君と違って
私は優しいんだ
Unlike you, I'm a kind man.
You sent those two assuming
that I'd defeat them, didn't you?
あの２人を
私にやられる前提で送りこんだな
To set Okkotsu off.
乙骨の起爆剤として
I trusted you.
そこは信用した
Trusted that a man as principled as you wouldn't
kill off young sorcerers without a reason.
オマエのような主義の人間は
若い術師を
理由もなく殺さないと
フッ… 信用か
Trust, huh?
I didn't think I still had any of that left.
まだ私にそんなものを
残していたのか
Return this for me, will you?
コレ 返しといてくれ
Was the elementary school your doing, too?
（五条）小学校も
オマエの仕業だったのか
Yeah.
まぁね
（五条）呆(あき)れた奴だ
I can't believe you.
Do you have any last words?
…何か言い残すことはあるか？
No matter what anyone says,
誰が何と言おうと
非術師(さるども)は嫌いだ
I hate those monkeys.
But I never held any hatred
for those in Jujutsu High.
でも… 別に高専の連中まで
憎かったわけじゃない
I just couldn't wear a
heartfelt smile in this world.
ただこの世界では
私は心の底から笑えなかった
Suguru.
傑…
（…）
はっ 最期くらい
呪いの言葉を吐けよ
At least hit me with some curses at my end.
（バシュ）
（真希）おい
（パンダ）憂太
- Hey! Hey!
- Yuta! Yuta!
（真希）おい
（パンダ）憂太
Hey!
（真希）おい！
おい 憂太！ 大丈夫か
Hey, Yuta! Are you okay?!
高菜
Mustard leaf.
しっかりしろ　憂太！
Wake up, Yuta!
Oh, he's awake.
あ しっかりした
ハッ…
Everyone...
みんな
Your injuries...
怪我… 真希さん
Maki-san. Inumaki-kun.
狗巻君
Wait! Panda-kun, your arm isn't healed!
ああっ パンダ君 腕治ってない
Chill out. We're all doing better
than you right now.
落ち着け
全員 今の憂太より元気だ
Unlike these other two,
my arm can be fixed later.
俺の腕は２人と違って
後でどうにでもなる
Thanks for saving us.
助けてくれてありがとうな
しゃけ
Salmon.
〜〜っ
Yuta...
（里香）憂太
（パンダ）ん？
Sorry, Rika-chan.
ごめんね 里香ちゃん
待たせたね
I've kept you waiting.
What's the matter, Yuta?
（パンダ）どーした？ 憂太
（乙骨）あ…
Well, uh...
えっと…
In exchange for borrowing her power,
…力を貸してもらう代わりに
um, I promised to go with Rika-chan.
あの… 里香ちゃんと
同じところに逝く約束をですね…
What?!
（真希）はぁ!? オマエ
それ死ぬってことじゃねーか！
Don't you know that means dying?!
What were you thinking, you idiot?!
何 考えてんだ バカ！
Uh, well, ...
（乙骨）ええと… いや それが…
Huh?
（乙骨・棘・パンダ）え…
（真希）？
Rika-chan?
（乙骨）里香ちゃん？
Congratulations.
おめでとう
You managed to break the curse.
解呪達成だね
Who are you?
（真希・乙骨・パンダ）誰？
Your good-looking guy, Gojo Satoru-sensei!
グッドルッキングガイ
五条悟先生ダヨ〜
以前 憂太が立てた仮説
面白いと思ってね
I thought the theory Yuta came
up with sounded interesting,
so I requested an investigation
into your family.
家系の調査を依頼した
The investigation of Rika's was
finished quite a long time ago,
里香のほうは
随分 昔に終了してたけど
but Yuta's was full of holes at best.
憂太のほうは
ザルもいいとこだったからね
それで判明したんだけど
So then it came to light.
You're the descendant of Sugawara Michizane!
君 菅原道真(すがわらのみちざね)
の子孫だった
That makes us super distant relatives!
超遠縁だけど僕の親戚！
Suga?!
（パンダ・真希）スガッ？
（乙骨）えっ 誰？
Yay! Yay! Yay! Yuta, yay!
Huh? Who?
One of Japan's three great apparitions!
日本三大怨霊の１人
超大物呪術師だ
He's a super bigshot sorcerer.
Tuna.
ツナ
You were right, Yuta.
憂太が正しかった
里香が君に呪いをかけたんじゃない
Rika didn't place a curse on you.
君が里香に呪いをかけたんだ
You placed a curse on Rika.
Rika-chan...
（乙骨の声）里香ちゃん…
どうしよう？ 死んじゃうの？
助けなきゃ！
What do I do?! Is she going to die?!
I have to save her!
死んじゃ駄目だ
死んじゃ駄目だ…
Don't die! Don't die!
Don't die! Don't die! Don't die!
死んじゃ駄目だ！
That's right.
そうだ
Back then, I rejected Rika-chan's death.
僕はあの時
里香ちゃんの死を拒んだ
Now the one who placed
the curse has canceled the bond.
（五条）呪いをかけた側が
主従制約を破棄したんだ
So long as the one who was cursed
doesn't seek any penalty,
かけられた側が罰(ペナルティー)を
望んでいないのであれば
it's fully broken now.
解呪は完了だ
Of course, that much was obvious
after seeing her in that form.
ま その姿を見れば
分かりきったことだよね
It was all my fault, wasn't it?
（乙骨）…全部 僕のせいじゃないか
I turned you into that form,
里香ちゃんをあんな姿にして
たくさんの人を傷つけて
I hurt all those people,
僕が夏油に狙われたせいで
みんなが死にかけた
and I nearly caused everyone to die
when Geto came after me!
It's all...
全部っ…
全部… 僕が…！
It's all my...
Yuta, thank you...
（里香）憂太　ありがとう
for giving me more time,
時間もくれて
ずっと側においてくれて
and letting me stay by your side.
These past six years,
里香はこの６年が
生きてる時より幸せだったよ
I've been happier than I ever was while alive.
（乙骨の泣き声）
（乙骨）！
（里香）バイバイ　元気でね
Bye-bye. Take care.
And don't come over here too soon, okay?
あんまり早く
こっちに来ちゃダメだよ
…うん
Okay.
See you later.
またね
It's a hit late now,
（五条）今さらだが夏油の件
君に非はない
but you weren't at fault
for the incident with Geto.
He would've come to Jujutsu High
whether you were there or not.
憂太がいなくても
アイツは必ず高専に来た
You think so?
ですかね
Also, here.
（五条）それから これ
（乙骨）あっ 学生証
Oh, my student ID.
You found it for me, Sensei?
先生が拾ってくれてたんだ
No, not me.
いや　僕じゃない
My best friend.
僕の親友だよ
The only one I had.
たった１人のね
Come on, Yuta! How long are
you gonna keep us waiting?
（真希）オラ 憂太！
いつまで待たせんだ！
Let's go!
行くぞ
Yeah.
（乙骨）うん
Theatrical Release
JUJUTSU KAISEN
♪ あなたが望むなら
この胸を射通して
♪ 頼りの無い僕もいつか
♪ 何者かに成れたなら
♪ 訳もなく
涙が溢れそうな
♪ 夜を埋め尽くす
♪ 輝く夢と成る
♪ 白い息は頼りなく
♪ 冬の寒さに溶けて消えた
♪ あの日の重ねた手と手の
♪ 余熱じゃあまりに頼りないの
♪ 春はいつだって
当たり前の様に
♪ 迎えに来ると
♪ そう思っていたあの頃
♪ 瞼閉じれば
夢はいつだって
♪ 正夢だと
信じてたあの頃
♪ あなたが望むなら
何処迄も飛べるから
♪ 意気地の無い僕もいつか
♪ 生きる意味を
見つけたなら
♪ 愛と憎を
聢と繋ぎ合わせて
♪ 一生醒めない程の
♪ 荒んだ夢と成る
♪ 凍える夜空を
二人で抜け出すの
♪ あたたかいコートを
そっと掛けたなら
♪ あなたはいつだって
♪ 当たり前の様に
隣にいると
♪ そう思っていたあの頃
♪ 失くせやしない
記憶の雨が古傷へと
♪ 沁み渡ろうとも
♪ あなたが望むなら
この胸を射通して
♪ 頼りの無い僕もいつか
♪ 何者かに成れたなら
♪ 訳もなく
涙が溢れそうな
♪ 夜を埋め尽くす
♪ 輝く夢と成る
♪ 記憶の海を潜って
♪ 愛の欠片を拾って
♪ あなたの中にずっと
♪ 眩しい世界をそっと
♪ この愛が
例え呪いのように
♪ じんわりとじんわりと
♪ この身体蝕んだとしても
♪ 心の奥底から
あなたが溢れ出して
♪ 求め合って重なり合う
♪ その先で僕ら夢と成れ
♪ あなたが望むなら
この胸を射通して
♪ 頼りの無い僕もいつか
♪ 何者かに成れたなら
♪ 訳もなく
涙が溢れそうな
♪ 夜を埋め尽くす
♪ 輝く夢と成る
♪ 正夢でも、
逆夢だとしても
♪ 最期にもう一度
強く抱きしめて
♪ その後はもう
何も要らないよ
♪ 僕の未来も
過去も何もかも
♪ あなたで満ちれば
後悔は無いよ
♪ 生きてる証刻むの
♪ 悴む心震わして
♪ 天秤なんて必要ないの
♪ 矛盾に脳を惑わして
♪ 正義と悪など
揺らいでしまう程
♪ 生き急いでいた
エンドロールは
♪ きっと神様の
身勝手な悪戯
♪ 汚れ役だろうと
厭わないよ
♪ 矛盾だらけ
お互い様ね
♪ 不幸話の背比べ
♪ 首の皮一枚
瀬戸際に
♪ 足掻いてちゃ
白々しいね
♪ ひとひらの想いよ
♪ 届け届けと
血を巡らせて
♪ 一途に見つめます
♪ 理由なんて必要は無いの
♪ 涙の理由も知らずに
♪ 愛が体を喰いちぎった
♪ 正しさを
振りかざさないで
♪ 事実が理由を
喰いちぎった
♪ 鼓動が止まぬように
♪ 喧噪に薪を焚べんだ
♪ 帳を張る事すら
♪ 無粋な気がしてんだ
♪ さあ来世に期待ね
♪ 光れ閃け猛スピードで
♪ 一途に向かいます
♪ 余力残す気は無いの
♪ 届け届けと
血を巡らせて
♪ 一途に愛します
♪ 永遠なんて
必要は無いの
♪ 最期にもう一度
強く抱きしめて
♪ その後はもう
何も要らないよ
♪ 見えない未来も
消せぬ過去さえも
♪ あなたで満ちれば
後悔はないよ
♪ 最期にもう一度
力を貸して
♪ その後はもう
何も要らないよ
♪ 僕も未来も心も体も
♪ あなたにあげるよ
全部全部
This is good.
おいひい
Isn't it?
ウマイダロ
“ロコイ”ッテ調味料ヲ
使ッテテナ
I used a spice called Royco.
That gives it a good flavor.
ソレガイイ味ヲダシテル
へぇ〜
Royco is a magic powder that makes
everything taste Kenyan when you add it.
（ミゲル）ロコイヲ入レレバ
何デモケニア味ニナル
魔法ノ粉ダ
More importantly,
they really went home, right?
ソレヨリ ヤツハ
本当ニ帰ッタンダナ
Yeah.
うん
Good, then.
ナライイ
This really is good. It's like nikujaga.
（乙骨）これ本当においしいね
肉じゃがみたい
肉ジャガ？
Nikujaga?
ビーフシチュート言エ
ビーフシチュート
Call it beef stew. Beef stew!
ン…
ん？ どうしたの
What's wrong?
What are you doing here?
何デ… オ前ガココニ？
Huh?
あれ？
Sensei?
先生
Hey. Long time no see.
やっ 久しぶり